Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Daniel Maruahal



Steinhauserstraße 3, Wohnung 285, Munich 81677, Germany

(+49)177 398 4427

🔀 daniel.maruahal@tum.de/danielmaruahal@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 10/03/1993 | Nationality Indonesia



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly logical, four-language speaking and self-motivated electrical engineer and data analyst with almost 5 years of experience assisting the development of electrical systems and data analyzing for vehicle performance and marketing in semiconductor and automotive industry. Eager to support company's driving decision making and developing insightful products by using data, statistics as well as data visualization. Currently, completed SQL Server database training and mastering Python for data analysis and Tableau for data visualization, beside electrical analysis. Boosted application promotion and product efficiency by 25% at Infineon Technologies in Germany and consistently implemented a set of procedures that reduced electrical examination for an automotive control system error down to 0.1% at Keihin in Japan.

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2020 - Present

Working Student and Master Thesis Student (from May 1st, 2022)

Infineon Technologies AG

Am Campeon 1-15 85579 Neubiberg, Germany

 Application Management and Marketing - Automotive market trends, analysis and report by utilizing block diagram builder, Ms. Excel, Visual Basic and Tableau for data analysis and visualisation Business or sector Semiconductor - Automotive Main Inverter and Business Strategy

February 2020 - July 2020

Working Student

Infineon Technologies AG

Am Campeon 1-15 85579 Neubiberg, Germany

 Germany—Japan Business Support (Intercultural Workshop - Taishi Dan Internal Community, internal communication and promotion by using internal intranet webpage and cloud share)

Business or sector Semiconductor - Automotive and Industrial Power Control and Business Strategy

April 2016 - April 2019

Electrical Engineer

Keihin Tochigi R&D Corporation

₹ 329-1233 2021-8 Hoshakuji, Takanezawa Town, Shioya County, Tochigi Prefecture, Japan

• Enforce electric circuit improvement and examination for CBR500 Honda ECU (Engine Control Unit) Business or sector Automotive

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

October 2019 – Present

Master of Science in Sustainable Resources Management

Technical University of Munich, Germany

 Study in progress supported by Deutschlandstipendium scholarship; planning to be specialized in Renewable Resources together with Environmental Economics & Policy, current GPA 1.8 out of 5.0.

October 2015 - March 2016

Japanese Language and Manner Training

CBS Techno Nagoya, Japan

Mastering Japanese for working in Japan.

July 2011 – August 2015

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Bandung Institute of Technology, Indonesia

• Achieving bachelor's degree in the major of electrical engineering with GPA 3.51 out of 4.00.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) Other language(s)

Bahasa Indonesia (Indonesian)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING		
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	WRITING		
B2/C1	C1	B2	C1	C1		
IELTS Certificate (Overall Score of 6.5)						
C1	B2	C1	C1/C2	C1		
JLPT Certificate (N2 Level)						
B1/B2	B1/B2	B1/B2	B1/B2	B1/B2		
B2 Level Courses at Technical University of Munich						

Japanese

English

-

German

Levels: A1/A2 Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Good communication skills gained through my experience as a project member team of electrical engineer in Japan as well as automotive management team in Germany.
- Teamwork (get used to teamwork and do an integrated partial work among the team members).
- Listening (grasp and summarize supervisor demand and implement it properly on work).

Organisational / managerial skills

- Leadership (have taken the responsible for a bachelor's degree final project team of 3 people and managed company's team activity as leader towards total 20 members).
- Motivation (mentoring 2 new Japanese comrades in an engaging and supportive fashion).

Job-related skills

- Calculation and precision of measurement in any electrical and mathematical problems.
- Data collection, organization, analysis, and visualization using below-mentioned software tools

Digital competence

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user		

Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user Digital competences - Self-assessment grid

- Excellent command of Microsoft Office suites (word processor, spread sheet, presentation software).
- Excellent data analysis in Scikit-Learn (and Python) Environment and data visualization with Tableau.
- Mastering responsive website front-end development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript codes.
- Familiar with Python and C programming language.
- Familiar with database developing program: Microsoft SQL Server
- Familiar with engineering design tools: MATLAB, Altium Designer, Multisim, and Altera Quartus.
- Familiar with sound-video editing with software tools such as Audacity and Adobe After Effects.

Other skills

- Electrical soldering and carpentry.
- Sports (football/futsal, swimming, and badminton).
- Playing musical instruments (piano and guitar).

Driving licence

B (International, Motor vehicles, having a permissible maximum mass not exceeding 3.500 kg and not more than 8 seats in addition to the driver's seat).

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Training and Seminars

- "SQL Server, Skicit-Learn, & Python Data Analysis Programming" trainings at Coding Studio (2022)
- "Silicon Carbide Technology Basics" Training at Infineon Technologies AG, Munich, Germany (2021).
- "Talk Digitalization" at Infineon Technologies AG, Munich, Germany (2020).
- "SRM Talks on Renewable Resources" in TUM Weihenstephan, Germany (2019).
- John Robert Powers Human Development Training in Jakarta, Indonesia (2019, still active).